Guide to the United Association of Journeymen and Apprentices of the Plumbing and Pipe Fitting Industry, Local 2 Records WAG.172
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
United Association of Journeymen and Apprentices of the Plumbing and Pipe Fitting Industry, Local 2 Records
1945-1995
1970-1992
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
United Association of Journeymen and Apprentices of the Plumbing and Pipe Fitting Industry. Plumbers Local 2 (Manhattan)
WAG.172
39.25 Linear Feet in 38 record cartons, 2 manuscript boxes, and 1 folder in a shared box.
3.55 Megabytes
1 videocassette
3 audiocassettes
United Association of Journeymen and Apprentices of the Plumbing and Pipe Fitting Industry, Local 2 represented workers in the plumbing industry in Manhattan and the Bronx from the late 19th century until the late 1990s. This collection contains documents and photographs relating to the union's activities from the mid-1940s through early 1990s. The bulk of the collection is from after 1970. Materials include legal briefs, case files, correspondence, administrative files, education materials, and photographs.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Arrangement
This collection has not been arranged by an archivist. The materials are arranged in the order in which they were received from the donor.
Scope and Contents
The United Association of Journeymen and Apprentices of the Plumbing and Pipe Fitting Industry, Local 2 Records contain documents and photographs relating to the union's activities from the mid-1940s through early 1990s. The bulk of the collection is from after 1970. Materials include legal briefs, case files, correspondence, administrative files, education materials, and photographs.
Related Archival Materials
Materials related to the government investigation and trial of the officials of Local 2 can be found in Series IV of the James McNamara Papers (WAG 129).
Historical Note
United Association of Journeymen and Apprentices of the Plumbing and Pipe Fitting Industry, Local 2 represented workers in the plumbing industry in Manhattan and the Bronx from the late 19th century until the late 1990s. The local was plagued by corruption, and in 1993, the national appointed a trustee to run the local. In 1997, Local 2 was dissolved and its members placed into the jurisdiction of Local 1.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by the United Association of Journeymen and Apprentices of the Plumbing and Pipe Fitting Industry, Local 1, 2001. The accession numbers 2002.025 and 2002.026 are associated with this gift.
Audiovisual Access Policies and Procedures
Audiovisual materials have not been preserved and may not be available to researchers. Materials not yet digitized will need to have access copies made before they can be used. To request an access copy, or if you are unsure if an item has been digitized, please contact tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A staff member will respond to you with further information.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Advance notice is required for the use of computer records. Original physical digital media is restricted. Born-digital materials have not been transferred and may not be available to researchers. Researchers may request access copies. To request that material be transferred, or if you are unsure if material has been transferred, please contact tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A staff member will respond to you with further information.
Appraisal
Water-damaged materials were deaccessioned during offsite preparation activities.
Briefs (legal documents); Legal documents.; Correspondence.; Legal files.; Photographs.; Labor unions -- New York (State); Labor unions -- New York (State) -- New York.; United Association of Journeymen and Apprentices of the Plumbing and Pipe Fitting Industry; United Association of Journeymen and Apprentices of the Plumbing and Pipe Fitting Industry. Plumbers Local 2 (Manhattan); United Association of Journeymen and Apprentices of the Plumbing and Pipe Fitting Industry. Plumbers Local 2 (Manhattan)
- Minutes of Constitution Committee; Real estate records; Training tests; Written tests; Convention travel expenses, Tax returns; Mike Celletti correspondence; Baseball league correspondence; Trial transcripts, 1969-1992; 453316 (Box 4)
- Administrative and education files, 1991-1992; 453323 (Box 5)
- Administrative and education files; Legal briefs; Arbitrations; General files, 1984-1992; 453324 (Box 6)
- Legal briefs; Open files; General correspondence, 1982-1990; 453327 (Box 7)
- National Pension Fund correspondence, 1985-1989; 453329 (Box 8)
- National Labor Relations Board cases, 1975-1992; 453330 (Box 9)
- Legal briefs, 1988-1991; 453331 (Box 10)
- Legal briefs, 1988-1992; 453332 (Box 11)
- Legal briefs; Correspondence and briefs (by contractor), 1987-1992; 453333 (Box 12)
- Correspondence and briefs (by contractor); Year-end dues and save history, 1977-1994; 453335 (Box 13)
- Correspondence regarding bonds, pensions, etc., 1986-1992; 453336 (Box 14)
- Contractor correspondence and general files; Negotiations, 1982-1992; 453338 (Box 15)
- General files; Case files; Event invitations, correspondence, attendee lists, etc.; Meeting minutes and agendas; Rally and demonstration notices, 1984-1992; 453339 (Box 16)
- Correspondence; Case files; Agreements and Contracts, 1988-1991; 453340 (Box 17)
- General files; Case files; Correspondence; Events, meetings, conferences and conventions material, 1988-1992; 453341 (Box 18)
- Correspondence; Conventions material; Agreements; Case files; Financial documents, 1982-1991; 453342 (Box 19)
- Correspondence; Meeting minutes and memos; Committee materials; Event invitations, flyers, correspondence; Materials documenting city and state legislative activities re: housing; Financial reports; Case files; Petty cash ledger, 1945-1993; 453343 (Box 20)
- Regular membership meetings minutes; Work-Trainee program material; Joint Apprenticeship Committee material; Contracts and agreements; Correspondence, legal briefs, and financial statements; Reciprocal agreements, 1969-1988; 453345 (Box 21)
- General files; Correspondence and memos; Event, dinner, meeting, and conference minutes, notices, and correspondence; Grant applications; Case files, 1986-1992; 453349 (Box 22)
- Legal briefs; VHS tape "Respondents' Exhibit 4", 1988, 1991; 453350 (Box 23)
- General correspondence and memos; Reciprocal agreements; Legal briefs; Event materials, 1982-1992; 453351 (Box 24)
- General correspondence and memos; Case files; Legal briefs; /legal briefs; Agreements; National Pension Fund correspondence files, 1991-1992; 453352 (Box 25)
- Death records; Pension Committee meeting minutes; General files; 3 audiocassette tapes, 1986-1989; 453353 (Box 26)
- Death records, 1984-1989; 453354 (Box 27)
- Death records, 1984-1985; 453355 (Box 28)
- Death records; Correspondence; Local 2 constitutions; Test papers (apprentices); Weekly job reports; Contracts; Policy paper on minimum wage (Frank Barbaro); Case files; Legal briefs, 1970, 1984-1992; 453356 (Box 29)
- Weekly job reports, 1988; 453358 (Box 30)
- Weekly job reports; Death records, 1988, 1993 (Box 40)
- Correspondence; Legal briefs; Case files; Weekly reports, 1986-1987; 453361 (Box 31)
- Correspondence; Weekly reports; Legal briefs; Agreements, 1982-1987; 453362 (Box 32)
- Correspondence; Weekly reports; Legal briefs; Agreements, 1982-1987; 453363 (Box 33)
- Legal correspondence; Membership dues; Local 2 constitution amendments and bylaws drafts, 1985-1988; 453364 (Box 34)
- Legal briefs and correspondence; Local 2 negotiations; Local 2 constitution amendments and bylaws drafts, Local 2 investigation, 1985-1990; 453365 (Box 35)
- Negotiating Committee reports; Executive Board minutes; Souvenir programs, 1970-1981; 453366 (Box 36)
- Local PAC research; Death records, 1986-1993; 453371 (Box 37)
- Legal briefs and correspondence; Death records; Examining board letters; Apprenticeship questions; Weekly reports; Member photographs, 1986-1992; 453375 (Box 38)
- Death records; Legal briefs and correspondence; Weekly reports, 1986-1995; 453377 (Box 39)
- Annual Entertainment and Ball Committee Group Portraits, 1954-1961; 544941 (Box OS001, Folder 1)
- Audiovisual Material – Respondents' Exhibit "4" / Typical 3/4 Inch Water Meter Installation, 1988 (Box Shared Tamiment 056)
- Audiovisual Material – #3, circa 1980s (Box Shared Tamiment 067)
- Audiovisual Material – #4, circa 1980s (Box Shared Tamiment 067)
- Audiovisual Material – #5, circa 1980s (Box Shared Tamiment 067)